PAUL SPENCER

Software Engineer

+31 6 46 395 141

• Amsterdam, The Netherlands

British and Irish (EU)

in linkedin.com/in/spencerpj

spencerpj.com

github.com/McFunshine

Summary

Software engineer with nearly three decades of delivering innovative solutions across fintech, energy, and govtech sectors, including 13 years specialized in .Net technologies. Completed a Master's in Software Engineering in 2022 while maintaining full-time employment. Currently architecting AI and emerging technology solutions while maintaining focus on practical business outcomes.

Experience

Khonraad Software Engineering

Lead AI and Emerging Technologies Architect

 $Amers foort, \ The \ Netherlands \\ Apr \ 2019-Present$

Technologies: Kotlin, Java, C#, Azure, OpenAI, Kotlin Multiplatform, JetBrains MPS, Python

- Production and innovation projects in the Mental Health Laws (WvGGZ)
- An example innovation project was A RAG chatbot, using .Net and Azure

Captain McFunshines Software Engineering

Freelance Software Engineer

Soest, The Netherlands Aug 2019 – Present

Technologies: Kotlin, Azure, AWS, OpenAI, Kotlin Multiplatform, Python

- Architected and implemented a new audio reversioning platform
- Five-month .Net consultancy engagement with Baker Hughes

Baker Hughes

Senior .Net Developer

Delft, The Netherlands Jan 2014 - Apr 2019

Technologies: C#, SQL Server

- Member of team that developed the SDK and API for the JewelSuite platform
- Served as principal technical contact for external developers building JewelSuite extensions
- Senior .Net contractor, managing quality and delivery of an offshore team

Kempen & Co

Senior .Net Developer

Amsterdam, The Netherlands May 2007 – Dec 2013

Technologies: C#, K2, SQL Server, VBA

- Delivered training on Entity Framework, Linq and Unit Testing/TDD
- Maintained and enhanced property securities indexing engine
- Developed application for maintaining and trading complex structured products
- Authored K2 Workflow (WWF) systems of business-critical processes

Unisys

Developer

Schiphol Rijk, The Netherlands May 2001 – May 2007

Technologies: VBA, WebIntelligence, C#

- Responsible for developing reporting for world wide Accounts Receivables

Achieved first Microsoft Certification and implemented small internal C# projects

ACT Financial Systems

London, UK

Developer Nov 1999 – Apr 2001

Technologies: PICK, Databasic, Universe, Visual Basic 6

- Responsible for developing and supporting a popular stockbroker settlement system

- Thirdline support for OMS a Visual Basic 6 wrapper on our settlement system

HSBC Investment Bank

London, UK

Developer Feb 1999 – Nov 1999

Technologies: PICK, Databasic, Universe

- Developed message processing, report writing, and screen handling programs

Lloyds Bank Stockbrokers

London, UK

Support / Business Analyst

May 1997 - Feb 1999

Technologies: PICK, Databasic, Universe, VBA, Visual Basic 4

- Support and Report Development for internal customers

- Took Visual Basic 4 night classes and thereafter implemented small internal projects

Education

Universiteit van Amsterdam

 $Amsterdam,\ The\ Netherlands$

Masters Software Engineering

Graduated 2022

Relevant Module: Software Construction - I created two interacting Domain Specific Languages using C# Note: Completed while maintaining full-time employment

Wolverhampton University

Wolverhampton, U.K.

BA European Business Administration

Graduated 1996

Hogeschool Holland

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

HEAO Joint European Business Administration

 $Graduated\ 1996$

Certifications

The Following Microsoft Professional Certifications:

- MCPD D425-8639 Windows Developer
- MCPD D418-3946 Windows Azure Developer (Charter Member)
- MCPD D415-8350 Web Developer
- MCPD A941-2480 Windows Developer
- MCPD A941-2479 Web Developer
- MCT D423-9678 .NET Framework, Windows Applications
- MCT D413-5519 .NET Framework, Data Access
- MCT D410-3346 . NET Framework, Web Applications
- MCT D404-5594 .NET Framework, Service Communication
- MCT A941-2481 . NET Framework, Windows Applications
- MCT A941-2482 . NET Framework, Web Applications
- MCSD C020-3599 Microsoft . NET
- MCAD C020-3597 Microsoft .NET
- MCP D020-3593 Microsoft Certified Professional
- Nederlands Als Een Tweede Taal (NT2) Niveau 2

Languages

- **English:** Mother Tongue
- Dutch: Fluent spoken, listening and reading, intermediate written